After a two week trial, a Wisconsin jury acquitted Kyle Rittenhouse
在经过两周的审判之后，Wisconsin陪审团裁定Kyle Rittenhouse无罪并当庭释放。
for shooting three people, killing two during a racial justice protest in Kenosha.
其曾在Kenosha的一次种族平等的抗议活动中开枪致2死1伤。
At the time Rittenhouse was a 17 year old from Illinois
案发时，Rittenhouse是一名来自伊利诺伊的17岁少年。
who traveled to Kenosha after right-wing
在右翼社交媒体的号召下，Rittenhouse来到
social media accounts called on people
Kenosha市，
to protect the city from riots.
以保护这座城市免受暴徒的破坏。
>- I am an EMT, if you
are injured come to me.
>- Rittenhouse acted in the
midst of a chaotic protest
>where many people were
legally carrying guns.
>Bystander video showed that the three men
>that Rittenhouse shot had been
in confrontations with him.
>Rittenhouse has now been found
not guilty on all six counts,
>arising from his conduct that day.
>- [Jury Member] We the
jury, find the defendant
>Kyle H. Rittenhouse not guilty.
>- So what happened at
the Rittenhouse trial?
>Why did the jury conclude
that he was not guilty?
>Is it a travesty of justice
or a defensible outcome?
>(light music)
>There's no dispute that
Rittenhouse killed two men
>and injured a third, but
as we talk about often
>on this channel, that's not
the end of the analysis.
>And here it was only the beginning.
>Many people thought that
when Kyle Rittenhouse
>admitted on the stand that he
intentionally use deadly force
>on Rosenbaum and Huber, that
was a huge tactical blunder.
>But intentional use of deadly force
>is exactly the thing that is privileged
>when you meet the
requirements of self-defense.
>And this case hinged on whether
self-defense applied or not.
>And more so than most self-defense cases,
>this case turned on the nuances
>of both self-defense law
and criminal procedure.
>It's not surprising to me that both sides
>got lots of stuff legally wrong.
>So let's talk about the law
of self-defense in Wisconsin,
>because every state has
different self-defense laws.
>And in Wisconsin, self-defense
like many other states,
>is an affirmative defense.
>In other words, the
defendant has the burden
>of producing some evidence.
>They must put forth some evidence
>from which a jury can find
that self-defense applied.
>This is generally called
the burden of production.
>But then, once the defense has made
>this relatively minimal burden,
>the burden of proof then
returns to the prosecution,
>which must disprove self-defense
beyond a reasonable doubt,
>which is the highest
standard in all of law.
>Now, every state has a self-defense law
>that basically says a person
who is not the aggressor
>is justified in using deadly force
>against an adversary when he
or she reasonably believes
>that they're in imminent danger
>of death or serious bodily injury.
>Now jurors aren't lawyers.
>So juries receive jury
instructions that include
>all the law that they will
need to decide a case,
>hopefully written in plain English.
>The lawyers and the judge fight
over the jury instructions,
>which will be the only law
that the jurors receive
>in that particular case.
>Now it is supposed to accurately summarize
>the law that the jurors are applying.
>And as you can imagine,
>the language of the jury instructions
>is extremely important.
>The Rittenhouse jury instructions
>summarize the requirements for
self-defense in Wisconsin as
>"the defendant believed
that there was an actual
>or imminent unlawful interference
>with the defendant's person.
>And the defendant believed
that the amount of force
>the defendant used or threatened to use
>was necessary to prevent or
terminate the interference
>and the defendant's
beliefs were reasonable.
>The defendant may intentionally use force,
>which is intended or likely to cause death
>or great bodily harm only if the defendant
>reasonably believed that
the force used was necessary
>to prevent death or great
bodily harm to himself."
>Now, in a situation like this,
>a reasonable belief doesn't mean true.
>One can have a reasonable
belief, but still be mistaken.
>Reasonableness is determined
from the standpoint
>of the defendant in
the situation at issue,
>not after the fact.
>And as an aside, the law of self-defense
>gets slightly more complicated
when you're applying it
>to different varieties of
homicide and manslaughter,
>because the mental state required
>is different for each of those offenses.
>But you can read the jury
instructions themselves
>and see how the court
modified the general rules
>that apply to self-defense
to apply to each
>of the different charges in this case.
>It's all written down in
relatively plain English,
>and it's worthwhile.
>You might be on a jury someday,
>and you might be faced with
similar jury instructions.
>Now, Wisconsin doesn't have
what's called a duty to retreat.
>In other words, Wisconsin
law doesn't require someone
>whose life is in danger to
exercise all opportunities
>to flee before resorting to deadly force.
>But, jurors can consider whether someone
>tried to move away from danger,
>as they assess the reasonableness
of a self-defense claim.
>Juries are still allowed to consider
>whether the defendant had
an opportunity to retreat
>to determine whether
or not it was necessary
>to use deadly force in self-defense.
>And Wisconsin law doesn't quite go as far
>as stand your ground states,
>which remove any consideration
of deescalating or fleeing
>before resorting to deadly force.
>However, as we'll talk about later,
>Wisconsin does have a duty to retreat
>where the person provokes
the attack against them.
>Now at common law, a
majority of jurisdictions
>require a duty to retreat
before being allowed to engage
>in deadly force in self-defense.
>But today, a duty to retreat is required
>in only a minority of US states.
>Here is a duty to retreat
instruction from Massachusetts.
>Quote, "a person cannot
lawfully act in self-defense
>unless he or she has exhausted
>all other reasonable alternatives
before resorting to force.
>A person may use physical
force in self-defense
>only if he or she could not
get out of the situation
>in some other way that was available
>and reasonable at the time.
>The Commonwealth," that is
the state of Massachusetts,
>"may prove the defendant
did not act in self-defense
>by proving beyond a reasonable doubt
>that the defendant resorted to force
>without using avenues of escape
>that were reasonably
available and which could not
>have exposed the defendant
to further danger."
>Again, that's the law of Massachusetts
>and it's not the law of Wisconsin.
>And it should go without
saying that the Kenosha jury
>was applying the law of
Wisconsin at the time.
>And we'll talk about the implications
>of this particular aspect of
Wisconsin law in a second.
>But the final nuance of
self-defense at issue
>is that of provocation.
>A person who provokes an attack
>cannot claim legal self-defense.
>But it's more complicated than just that.
>The Wisconsin law on provocation states,
>"a person who engages in unlawful conduct
>of a type likely to provoke
others to attack him or her,
>and thereby does provoke an attack
>is not entitled to claim the
privilege of self-defense
>against such attack, except
when the attack which ensues
>is of a type causing the person engaging
>in the unlawful conduct
to reasonably believe
>that he or she is an imminent danger
>of death or great bodily harm."
>Okay, so let's break down
this law on provocation,
>which is an exception to the
exception of self-defense,
>which is an exception to the ability
>to use deadly force against someone.
>So let's say you engage
in unlawful conduct
>likely to provoke others.
>Well, then you can't claim self-defense.
>Except that you can, if your
provocation causes others
>to use effectively
deadly force against you.
>Now we'll get back to this in a second,
>but the law continues.
>In such a case where the provoked attacker
>uses deadly force against the provoker,
>the person engaging in
the unlawful conduct
>is privileged to act in self-defense,
>but the person is not privileged
>to resort to the use of force
>intended or likely to cause
death to the person's assailant.
>Unless the person reasonably
believes that he or she
>has exhausted every other reasonable means
>to escape from or otherwise
avoid death or great bodily harm
>at the hands of his or her assailant.
>So here, you only get to use deadly force
>to resist the deadly
force that you provoked
>if you exercise a duty to retreat.
>Wisconsin law stipulates
that the provocateur
>must attempt every other
reasonable option to escape,
>avoid, or prevent the attack
>before resorting to deadly
force if they were the ones
>that provoked the secondary attack.
>Now we'll talk about the
general law of self-defense
>and whether it applies under
the factual circumstances
>as we know them in a second.
>But first I want to talk about
the exception of provocation
>because a number of people believe
>that Kyle Rittenhouse provoked
the attacks themselves,
>and therefore couldn't use
the privilege of self-defense.
>That by brandishing a firearm
>or placing himself in this situation,
>he provoked the attack.
>Now there's three issues here.
>First, is there unlawful conduct?
>Did Kyle Rittenhouse
engage in unlawful conduct
>that could constitute provocation
>and therefore prevent the
defense of self-defense?
>Well, Judge Schroeder granted
defense motions to dismiss
>the two misdemeanor charges
against Rittenhouse.
>I think a lot of people
put too much emphasis
>on those lesser included offenses.
>The charges were for possessing
>a dangerous weapon as a minor,
>and a misdemeanor charge
for breaking curfew.
>And arguably, Wisconsin
law has an exception
>that allows miners to
possess shotguns and rifles,
>as long as they're not short barreled.
>But more importantly, provocation requires
>unlawful conduct of a type
likely to provoke others.
>Now, even if those two lesser
included charges had stuck,
>they might not have been sufficient
>to rise to the level of provocation.
>Mainly because Wisconsin
is an open carry state.
>Mere open carry of a
firearm is A, not unlawful.
>And B, possibly not the type
>likely to lead to provoking others.
>Now I'm oversimplifying here.
>This is a highly fact-specific analysis,
>but it's not unreasonable
that someone might not find
>that the gun possession,
quad gun possession
>didn't lead to provocation.
>Think about it, is it
the possession of the gun
>that provokes the attack?
>Or is it the possession
of a gun by a minor
>or possession of a gun
that crossed state lines
>that leads to someone provoking an attack?
>If you think it's the former,
well, that's not illegal.
>And the latter probably
doesn't provoke an attack.
>No one says, oh, the
reason I'm attacking you
>is that you're a minor with a firearm,
>not that you're carrying a
firearm in the first place.
>And additionally, breaking curfew
>probably couldn't be
the requisite predicate
>because lots of people
were breaking curfew
>and it wasn't leading to mass provocation.
>Now, it's a closer call when
you consider Rittenhouse
>admitted that he pointed
his gun at the victims
>and claimed that when
he was pointing his gun,
>it wasn't a dangerous provocation.
>Now you could argue that
pointing your gun at someone
>is assault or misuse of a firearm,
>but that probably doesn't work
>if the reason that you're pointing the gun
>at someone in the first place
>is for the purposes of self-defense.
>And in fact, there are
Wisconsin cases to this effect.
>Though, on the other other hand,
>Wisconsin courts have
an interesting history
>in analyzing the provocation exception.
>For example, in a 1975
Wisconsin Supreme Court case,
>the court held that the
defendant was a provocateur
>by virtue of openly bringing
a gun into a tavern.
>The Wisconsin Supreme Court held quote,
>"the defendant himself testified
that after being slapped,
>he went out to his car, got his shotgun,
>loaded it and returned to the tavern.
>As he was entering the tavern,
>he was grabbed from the side by someone
>and he pushed that person away.
>He saw Freddy Jones start toward him
>and he started shooting.
>He stopped after four shots
>and after Jones was out of sight.
>The defendant requests that the court
>grant him a new trial in
the interest of justice.
>We find no merit to this contention.
>When the defendant left the tavern,
>got his shotgun out of the trunk,
>loaded it and returned to the tavern,
>he became the provoker.
>Additionally, there is an 1883
>Wisconsin Supreme Court case that says,
>quote, "if one points a
loaded gun at another,
>and the other grapples with
him to prevent the shooting
>and is shot, it is murder."
>And this is especially important
>in the context of the
Rittenhouse shooting.
>Even Rittenhouse's
testimony seems to indicate
>that Rosenbaum didn't lunge at Rittenhouse
>until he raised his gun at Rosenbaum.
>And that the reason, or at
least one of the reasons
>that Kyle Rittenhouse shot
Rosenbaum is that he feared
>that Rosenbaum would take his gun away
>and use it against him.
>And we'll talk about that in a second.
>And obviously, you'd have to
run a provocation analysis
>in every instance where Kyle
Rittenhouse used deadly force.
>It's not a one size fits all.
>You have to look at every
instance individually.
>And if the jury had found that there was
>nothing unlawful that led to provocation,
>or if there were illegal things going on,
>those weren't the ones that
were leading to the provocation,
>their analysis to this exception
>probably would have ended there.
>And they would have found
that provocation didn't apply.
>It's only where there is provocation
>do we get to the next questions.
>But, assuming that that
first hurdle had been met,
>you'd get to the next
one, imminent danger.
>Even when someone provokes an attack,
>they can regain the
right to use deadly force
>where that person
reasonably believes that he
>is in imminent danger of
death or great bodily harm.
>And he may lawfully act in self-defense.
>Since this is essentially
the same standard
>as self-defense in the first instance,
>given that the jury must have thought
>Kyle Rittenhouse acted in self-defense,
>they probably would have
found that this exception
>to the exception, to
the exception applied,
>even if they got to this question.
>And so if they got over
those two first hurdles,
>they then would have had to
get over the third hurdle,
>which is the duty to retreat.
>That's the final issue in terms of
>whether provocation can apply,
>assuming the first two hurdles are met.
>The third clause says that the person
>who provokes the attack
cannot use or threaten force,
>unless he believes that he has exhausted
>all other opportunities to escape.
>If the jury got to this question,
>they could have felt that he had no choice
>under the circumstances, we don't know.
>And one of the prior
issues might have precluded
>even getting to this question.
>But if the jury did reach this question,
>then they felt that Kyle Rittenhouse
>either had no opportunity to escape
>or had exhausted all
of those opportunities.
>If that's the case, whether Wisconsin had
>a general duty to retreat
might not have changed
>the overall outcome here anyway.
>Anyone who says that this is
a simple case of self-defense
>or that it's cut and
dry is definitely wrong.
>But so far, we've talked
about the exception
>to the exception, that is provocation.
>Let's now talk about whether
the original exception,
>self-defense, applied or
could reasonably have applied
>in this particular case.
>Let's talk about the facts as
we know them from the trial.
>Now, warning, these videos are graphic,
>but let's talk about what the relatively
>uncontested testimony
and these videos shows.
>Rittenhouse and his friend, Dominic Black
>testified that they went to Kenosha
>to protect a car dealership
called Car Source.
>The two owners of the
dealership told jurors
>that they never asked anyone
to protect Car Source.
>During the protest, a small
group of 8 to 9 people
>were gathered at the dealership.
>Kyle Rittenhouse, that night,
>was separated from the rest of his group
>and jogged towards one of
the Car Source parking lots.
>Kyle Rittenhouse apparently
sees Joshua Ziminski
>is nearby armed with a pistol.
>Rittenhouse continues to
run towards Car Source.
>Rosenbaum chases Kyle Rittenhouse.
>Rosenbaum throws a plastic
bag behind Kyle Rittenhouse,
>which lands on the ground.
>A shot is fired from someone
else about a hundred feet away.
>Kyle Rittenhouse turns around and stops
>as he gets to some parked cars
>and shoots the unarmed
Rosenbaum four times
>in quick succession, once in the back.
>(shots firing, people screaming)
>Kyle Rittenhouse then
runs away from the scene.
>A loose crowd starts to
follow Kyle Rittenhouse.
>- (man in crowd) That guy
shot someone, get (beep).
>- Rittenhouse trips, falls to the ground,
>sits up right and points his gun
>at one person who backs away.
>He shoots at a man who does
sort of a half jump kick,
>but backs away after the shot.
>At roughly the same time,
>Anthony Huber hits Kyle
Rittenhouse with a skateboard.
>Rittenhouse fires a shot.
>Huber picks up the
skateboard and runs away.
>Another shot is fired
in either the direction
>of Huber or Gaige Grosskreutz.
>Huber drops to the ground.
>Grosskreutzthen puts his hands
up while armed with a pistol.
>As he's making a move toward
>or to the side of Rittenhouse,
>Rittenhouse then fires at Grosskreutz
>hitting him once in the bicep.
>Now this is of course,
>a hopefully neutral oversimplification.
>There are a lot of other facts.
>But at base, this is a
confusing in-charge situation,
>even with video footage.
>And it's not an easy
case in either direction.
>So was this self-defense?
>You can look at those
facts and see a murder.
>You can look at those facts
and find self-defense.
>Two diametrically opposed beliefs
>can both be reasonable at the same time.
>There are a ton of open questions here.
>Was the use of force
proportionate in every encounter?
reasonable in every encounter?
>Did Rittenhouse provoke
any of those reactions?
>But the videos and testimonies show
>a chaotic situation and
people acting quickly.
>Now no blanket assertions can be made.
>You have to run the self-defense analysis
>for each incident individually,
>including the shots fired at the people
>that weren't Rosenbaum,
Huber or Grosskreutz.
>With the provocation argument aside,
>one might look at these
incidents in question
>and decide that they were self-defense.
>After all in the latter two incidents,
>Kyle Rittenhouse was fending off
>what was arguably an
attack with a skateboard
>and in another, the man admitted
>he drew a gun on Rittenhouse.
>But one might also reasonably conclude
>that one or more of these incidents
>were not self-defense and
were therefore murder.
>After all, in the first incidence,
>Rosenbaum, an unarmed man
threw a bag of clothes
>at Rittenhouse, which didn't
land anywhere near Rittenhouse.
>After which Rittenhouse
points his gun at him.
>And then Rosenbaum moves at Rittenhouse
>or apparently towards the gun,
>and Rittenhouse shoots him
four times, once in the back.
>And yes, I'm aware of Rittenhouse's
>self-serving testimony about
the preceding incidents.
>What I'm saying is that
reasonable minds can differ.
>And Rittenhouse also
shoots at, but misses,
>the unarmed jump-kick man.
>And latter incidents involving
Grosskreutz and Huber
>happened perhaps a few hundred feet away
>from several dozen police officers.
>It's not surprising that the
people who pursued Rittenhouse
>thought he was an active shooter
who needed to be stopped.
>But the only question
in this particular case
>was whether Rittenhouse's actions
>could possibly have been reasonable.
>Because remember, the standard is that
>the jury must find that
there is no reasonable doubts
>that it wasn't self-defense.
>It's possible, if not probable,
>that both Rittenhouse
and the people he killed
>were simultaneously
acting in self-defense.
>The fog of war is a real thing.
>Reasonable beliefs can be mistaken.
>The jury was accurately, based on the law,
>told that they had to determine
>whether Rittenhouse's
belief was reasonable
>based on the circumstances.
>And this reminds me of the story
>of Gabby Giffords and Joe Zamudio.
>when Giffords was shot
at a political rally,
>Joe Zamudio, who was legally armed,
>came running to help
when he heard the gunfire
>that injured Gabby Giffords and
killed six others in Tucson.
>By the time that Zamudio
came to the scene,
>unarmed civilians had already tackled
>and disarmed the perpetrator.
>Zamudio later said that in his confusion,
>he was within seconds of shooting
>one of the people that was
helping, not the shooter himself.
>This is an issue that
champions of Rittenhouse
>should grapple with.
>If Rosenbalm or Huber or Grosskreutz
>had killed Kyle Rittenhouse,
they might've been justified
>in using self-defense under the law.
>Again, reasonable minds
might differ on this.
>But any system that incentivizes rule
>by the last person standing,
>that is killing the only person
>who might dispute your
claim of self-defense.
>That seems well suboptimal.
>It's at this point, that
my notes simply say,
>vigilantism is bad.
>And I stand by that.
>I also worry that that is
becoming a controversial position.
>Net net bringing guns to a protest is bad.
>Anyone that brings it,
not just Kyle Rittenhouse.
>But there's a large strain
of people that simply say
>that Kyle Rittenhouse
shouldn't have been there.
>And that's the reason that
he can't use self-defense.
>And by most accounts,
>Kyle Rittenhouse meets the
definition of a vigilante.
>But whether Kyle Rittenhouse
should have been there
>in the first place isn't
relevant to the questions
>of whether he legally met the definition
>of self-defense in the first place.
>Just simply possessing a gun by itself,
>doesn't prevent the
application of self-defense.
>And there are of course, larger
social issues here as well.
>Many have claimed that it
would have been impossible
>for a black person to kill two people,
>injured a third and fire at a fourth
>and live to walk away from
the scene as Rittenhouse did.
>And then of course, to
be found, not guilty.
>And we can probably evaluate
whether this is true or not.
>One way to look at this
is by studying the data
>on how jury's perceive self-defense.
>a study by John Roman found that homicides
>with a white perpetrator
and a black victim
>are 10 times more likely
to be ruled justified
>than cases with a black
perpetrator and a white victim.
>And the gap is larger in states
with stand your ground laws.
>And after accounting for a
variety of confounding factors,
>such as whether the victim and
perpetrator were strangers,
>the gap is smaller, but still significant.
>Cases with a white
perpetrator and black victim
>are 281% more likely to be ruled justified
>than cases with a black
perpetrator and white victim.
>But systemic issues like
that weren't on trial here.
>You don't adjudicate those
kinds of systemic issues
>in a criminal court of one individual.
>The issue is whether Kyle Rittenhouse
>engaged in self-defense
or more specifically,
>whether the prosecution
disproved the possibility
>that he used self-defense.
>And for what it's worth,
there are lots of people
>who think that Kyle Rittenhouse's actions
>were not self-defense.
>There are lots of other reasonable people
>who think that Kyle Rittenhouse's
actions were self-defense.
>Now I doubt all of those
people in both of those groups
>watched 100% of the trial then spent days
>pouring over the jury instructions
>like the Kenosha jury did.
>But the thing is, if reasonable people
>really could conclude that
this was self-defense,
>then it means that the prosecution
>didn't prove self-defense
beyond a reasonable doubt.
>That's the definition of reasonable doubt.
>Now that being said, an
acquittal doesn't mean
>that Kyle Rittenhouse didn't do it.
>It doesn't mean that what Kyle
Rittenhouse did was right.
>And the pathology of Kyle Rittenhouse's
>hagiography is another issue entirely.
>And it certainly doesn't mean
that he did nothing wrong.
>It just means the jury didn't think
>that the prosecution proved self-defense
>beyond a reasonable doubt.
>And while you can't necessarily infer it
>from the jury's decision,
it might be the case
>that Kyle Rittenhouse did
nothing legally wrong.
>But under the most favorable
interpretations of the facts,
>Kyle Rittenhouse brought
gasoline to a match party
>and people are now dead as a result.
>He made a bad situation worse.
>And let's face it, if
someone uses non-deadly force
>against you while you are carrying a gun,
>it's more likely to turn deadly.
>Rosenbaum, jump-kick
man and arguably, Huber,
>used non-deadly force.
>Which would not in the abstract
>trigger a reasonable
belief of imminent harm.
>Which is not to say that unarmed people
>can't exercise deadly force
or create a reasonable belief
>of eminent, deadly harm,
they absolutely can.
>Indeed, it appears that the jury
>believed Rittenhouse's testimony
>that they were going for his gun
>or grabbed his gun in an
attempt to take his gun
>and use it against him.
>And in a huge stretch, in
Rittenhouse's speculation,
>take his gun and use it against others.
>Now, those arguing that,
but for Kyle Rittenhouse,
>being present with his gun,
>these shootings wouldn't
have happened are right.
>However, but for causation,
>or what we call sine qua non causation,
>it doesn't rise to the level of guilt
>beyond a reasonable doubt.
>It's necessary for a conviction,
but it's not sufficient.
>Now I've seen lots of people say, quote,
>"the jury reached the right verdict."
>Now there is a strong version
>and a weak version of that statement.
>The weak version is that
the jury was correct
>to find that there was reasonable doubt
>that Kyle Rittenhouse
didn't use self-defense.
>However, the strong
version is that the jury
>proactively found him
innocent or even a hero.
>But assuming we're going
with the weak version,
>it's entirely possible
that the jury verdict
>accurately reflects the law of Wisconsin.
>I've never seen a
politician run on a platform
>of installing a duty
to retreat in the law.
>If Wisconsin had a duty to retreat,
>the outcome of this case,
>very well might've been different.
>Stated differently, if this
had occurred in Massachusetts,
>the law could have militated
a different result.
>Though, admittedly, maybe reasonable minds
>might differ on that as well.
>Maybe Kyle Rittenhouse retreated
>at every possible opportunity.
>But I will leave it to you and
by proxy, your politicians,
>as to whether that is a
good thing or a bad thing.
>Though, I'll point out that for those
>that are happy that Kyle
Rittenhouse was found not guilty,
>they should recognize that logically,
>they should also be in favor
of an alternate reality
>where Gaige Grosskreutz shot
and killed Kyle Rittenhouse.
>And remember, if you think that
>Rosenbaum, Huber or Grosskreutz
>all provoked a response
from Kyle Rittenhouse,
>Rittenhouse's use of deadly force
>probably gave them the right
to use deadly force right back
>under the same laws.
>Under current Wisconsin
law, if Kyle Rittenhouse
>is not guilty, by reason of self-defense,
>Gaige Grosskreutz would
also have been not guilty
>if he had shot and
killed Kyle Rittenhouse.
>And keep in mind that in this scenario,
>Kyle Rittenhouse is dead
and it would have been
>Grosskreutz setting the narrative.
>And to the extent that
you think Grosskreutz
>would have crafted his
testimony to support
>an argument of self-defense,
>then consider that Kyle
Rittenhouse probably crafted
>his story in exactly the same way.
>So the ultimate takeaway here
>is that these incidents are murky at best.
>Occurred in a jurisdiction with very broad
>self-defense and firearm laws.
>The prosecution had a very
high standard to meet.
>And while we didn't
cover it in this video,
>the defendant put on a very good defense.
>The rest I will leave to you.
>Now, if you'd like to
watch something legal,
>that's much more lighthearted,
>I'd recommend my mini
documentary, "Bad Law Words Good"
>where I explore all of
the most common legal
>and linguistic comments
that people throw around
>in everyday life incorrectly.
>It is a hilarious and educational romp
>through legal misunderstandings,
logical fallacies,
>and law and order parodies.
>And it's only on Nebula,
which you can get for free
>with Curiosity Stream.
>Because Nebula is where I
release all my videos early,
>usually with extended cuts
and where I can experiment
>with content and put things
that I couldn't put on YouTube.
>And we're thrilled to be
partnering with today's sponsor
>Curiosity Stream, because
they're the go-to source
>for the best documentaries
>and long form educational
content on the internet.
>They even have an entire section
>devoted to unsolved mysteries and crime.
>So if you like my videos,
>you will love the stuff
on Curiosity Stream.
>And right now Curiosity Stream is offering
>42% off their annual plans.
>That's less than $12 for the entire year
>for both Curiosity Stream and Nebula.
>So if you click on the
link in the description
>or the one that's on screen right now,
>you'll get both Curiosity
Stream and Nebula
>for 42% off, or you can go
to curiositystream.com/legal.
>It's a great way to support this channel
>and educational content
directly for under $12 per year.
>And it's the only way
to see my documentary
>"Bad Law Words Good."
>So just click on the link
that's on screen right now,
>or the one that's in the description
>to get Curiosity Stream, Nebula
and "Bad Law Words Good."
>Plus, clicking on that link
really helps out this channel.
>And while you're there,
click on this playlist
>with all my other real law reviews.
>So click on that video
or I'll see you in court.